<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kylen.me</title>
    <link>https://kylen.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on kylen.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/legalcode&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 13:05:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kylen.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WW - Perspective</title>
      <link>https://kylen.me/posts/2022/07/ww-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 13:05:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kylen.me/posts/2022/07/ww-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Could humans really destroy all life on earth?, Humans exploiting and destroying nature on unprecedented scale, A looming mass extinction caused by humans.
The news loves it, people think about it, maybe some of us even talk about it. Are humans just plain evil? From one perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to think so. There&amp;rsquo;s countless examples of how our species seems to fuck up everything we touch.
We destroy the environment, wipe out other species, pollute the oceans, commit genocide, murder, and assault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Qubes on the Framework Laptop</title>
      <link>https://kylen.me/posts/2022/06/installing-qubes-on-the-framework-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:52:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kylen.me/posts/2022/06/installing-qubes-on-the-framework-laptop/</guid>
      <description>Gist from Github:
  Reproduced in text form (may be outdated): This was my process getting Qubes OS running on the Framework Laptop. I use a dark theme, and these are the scaling numbers that looked good to me. I also run debian minimal for all templates. XFCE. Specs: i5-1135G7, 16GB RAM, 512GB SN850 NVMe, AX210 no vPro
In the future I may try installing KDE, or salting some of this configuration, For now however, this is the list of settings I changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WW - Hello World</title>
      <link>https://kylen.me/posts/2022/06/ww-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kylen.me/posts/2022/06/ww-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>hello world
I would say that nearly every programmer in the world has written a so-called &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; program at some point in their journey.
This program, once launched, prints &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; to the screen and then exits. A very simple goal, but the countless ways to write such a program is a testament to the myriad of techniques and languages programmers use.
Diving a little deeper though, we see that underneath such a simple program, an immense amount of work is being done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things</title>
      <link>https://kylen.me/things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kylen.me/things/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! Here I will share anything I think is interesting. It might be random information, books, or videos, or articles, or quotes, anything of the sort. This page will (presumably) expand over time, and is perpetually a work-in-progress. I will add, remove, and change things frequently.
Because this page is long, and completely unordered, I highly suggest you utilize the table of contents.
 Interesting quote:
 A civilization which leaves so large a number of its participants unsatisfied and drives them into revolt neither has nor deserves the prospect of a lasting existence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
